Lies. Corruption. Murder. One reporter will break the silence.
Bordertown is a crime, drama, mystery film directed by Gregory Nava.
American corporations are using the North American Free Trade Agreement by opening
large maquiladoras right across the United States–Mexico border.
The maquiladoras hire mostly Mexican women to work long hours for
little money in order to produce mass quantity products.
Lauren Adrian, an impassioned American news reporter for the Chicago Sentinel
wants to be assigned to the Iraq front-lines to cover the war.
Instead, her editor George Morgan assigns her to investigate a series of slayings
involving young maquiladora factory women in a Mexican bordertown.
Lauren Adrian, played by Jennifer Lopez.
George Morgan, played by Martin Sheen.
Alfonso Diaz, played by Antonio Banderas.
Eva Jimenez, played by Maya Zapata.
Teresa Casillas, played by Sônia Braga.
Elena Diaz, played by Kate del Castillo.
Bordertown is a 2007 American crime drama film written and directed by Gregory Nava, and starring Jennifer Lopez
(who also served as a producer), Martin Sheen, Maya Zapata, Sônia Braga and Antonio Banderas.
This is the third film which featured the collaboration between Nava and Lopez,
following the 1997's biopic film Selena and 1995's My Family.
The film is inspired by the true story of the numerous female homicides in Ciudad Juárez originally brought to light in documentaries produced by
Tom Golden and tells the story of an inquisitive American reporter sent in by her American newspaper to investigate the murders.
Lopez also recorded a song for the film entitled Porque La Vida Es Asi.
The film explores themes of journalist, rape,
corruption, threat of death, cuidad juarez.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.